That's pretty for both job load and job
preload.
OK,
So I would love to get some time to to go
through the previous recording.
I had a four days.
Yeah, I'm not for the.
That's fine.
I told you the broker one only today
because it has the implementation also
and you can then provide me the path and
the yeah,
bad recognition just implemented for
count.
It's a dummy one.
Most probably it would.
Anyway, I'll be doing it for CCO also.
But for today I'll give this task load.
It is.
It's invalid because of some connection
issues.
Just ignore this.
OK, so from the batch task flow,
I have just opened the job level task
flow here after job reload.
This is a job load.
Job load consists of 2 steps, 22 steps.
One is from source to stage and then
stage to target these two.
This mapping task will do source to stage
load and this mapping task will have a
match query which will do the upset
operation on the target table.
OK,
let's go through ABC related stuff would
be there only in source to stage one.
Let me open this mapping task and one
more thing, Aishwarya,
so this is regarding the job load, right?
Is there any recording for int when know
how we are like what we are changing?
Suppose we are keeping a new task load or
anything and right.
And also the GitHub and all like you
mentioned in the previous call that you
guys are uploading the and all right,
those all processes like basically int
when what is happening?
Is there any already recording only or
not one recording area.
So this is a recording.
We are part of this USA working team,
right?
So this is your part, right?
You are part of this team, right?
OK, so here this is the recording.
So first time all our ABC components are
in common folder, right?
How to copy them into our domain level
ABC folder and what changes need to be
done to them and how to prepare batch
predequisite task flow, batch task flow,
job level task flow,
all these details are covered here, OK.
How to assign input fields,
everything is covered here in this
recording.
OK,
I have shared multiple records endings on
that which it here is your build.
Is there one question?
So like is there any tracker or anything?
Then you put the recording link and what
is it about the subject or something?
Yeah,
most probably the names are just RIA,
only that one is bit different.
That's why I've just shared it again.
OK, this is IDMC build right here.
I have explained how to integrate ABC
within the mappings.
OK.
And this ABC metadata,
ABC metadata or related to ABC metadata
entries, OK,
how to make ABC metadata entries into
tables and how how we are using it like
similar to ABC metadata entries,
these two.
And this is ABC task flow implementation.
OK, this is related to end to end,
how to implement the ABC task job level
task flow and how to create the parameter
file.
This is related to CCO.
CCO we have created job level task force
only, right?
How to create the task flow,
how to provide the input parameter and
where,
where the parameter files you we have how
we are loading especially everything.
Yeah, GitHub is a different thing.
Everyone in the team knows about it,
but I don't know whether there is.
I think we have to check with Gayathri
for that GitHub related related info,
like related recording.
OK, It it's, it's just,
it's a simple thing.
If you just see once how it is doing,
you will get it.
Yeah, even like everyone,
almost everyone in the team knows how to
upload parameter file and how to do pull
request merge, how to do merge,
everything they know.
But if you want,
we can check with guy three.
You can directly ask guy three if there
is any recording on how to do a pull
request in GitHub while we are uploading
it to the main branch.
OK here in this file we have I have just
covered mostly related to the ABC ABC
task flow ABC meta data entries and
parameter file and this is IDMC build.
OK this this is the link where which I
have given in the below.
OK this is the framework related flow
flow how ABC works.
It's it's a old video,
but it has most of the details.
OK,
this is framework high level framework
flow walkthrough.
And this is how to copy the components
from the common folder to here and how
what needs to be updated and and these
two are related to metadata entries and
these two are related to build,
how to integrate ABC in the mappings and
all.
And this is related to parameter file,
task flow and overall related to APC for
all related to ABC in CCO.
So this would be helpful.
And one more thing how to make dummy mock
up entries in runtime entries,
sorry runtime tables.
So in ABC runtime tables as we are
dependent on zone one,
we are making some dummy mock up runtime
entries for unit testing that that is
this recording.
So we have all these recordings in place
under the under 1 folder.
This folder the dummy runtime entries.
So we are dependent on zone 1 table right?
You are seeing that in ETL detangation
window we are populating job run ID of
source table,
job status of source table into that
table right?
So how will we get those entries?
We must have some runtime entries for
source tables also right here for few
tables there are no runtime in entries in
a proper condition.
So that is the reason why we made runtime
entries even for source tables for first
time incremental and current run.
I have given all the details here in this
talk,
in this video and those speaks Aishwarya,
like do you have those entries like you
mentioned about some speaks are there
right that we'll share for metadata
entries and then for CCO?
No, no, the ABC data entry, OK,
metadata and runtime metadata and untime
both you mentioned, right,
there are some speed and also some CCO
related one which is for the script, OK,
I have shared with you.
I don't know,
I think I have shared with you.
Let me check whether I have shared with
you or not.
ABC metadata entries I have shared with
Churi already.
You can go through This is related to
metadata entries.
If you go to the same path,
you will get the runtime entries.
Also, I'll give you that SharePoint link.
You'll have all the things related to IB,
the CCO.
Oh, this is ABC metadata entries, right.
I'll give you this link.
It's in VDI.
It it, Yeah, it's in VDI.
This is metadata entries, runtime entries.
These are solely for unit testing.
OK,
we should not make any entries in any
other environment.
This is solely for unit testing until and
unless like we are making it as there is
no proper source runtime entries and also
there is no logic for first time
incremental only.
For that reason we are making and you you
can ignore any other parameter files.
You can see here that you don't need,
I think more than that for APC.
For APC I have given you that link.
What else?
What else do you need?
Like resources, We are good, I guess.
I think like that.
Is there anything else that is needed
from I don't think RIA like I think we
are good.
We know OK if you talk about build,
how to create the query and all like
there are videos.
I think you have to check with Bharat.
He has explained it in in the start of
the build itself like he will give you
like but it has given us KT how to frame
the query Android.
So based upon that we have that OK here
coming to the job load and where is that
kitting like do you have the link?
I don't know,
I think it would be mostly in this link
only Yeah,
we have to check this is in Deloitte, OK,
under the render phase.
I don't know why it is showing.
Yeah, go back and then again come to the.
Should I repeat the recording folder,
go back to the previous folder,
parent folder and then come back to No,
no, it is not.
It's not only it's OK.
I think the other recordings would be
available like would be accessible I
guess.
I think this the last link is there right
here.
We'll have all the recordings.
Oh, what is this?
What happened?
Not sure.
Yeah, check from your end as well.
We can check with.
I have uploaded all these things there
only.
I don't know if I if I'm only facing this
issue or everyone is facing this issue.
OK,
let it be real like we can check with the
team.
Let's start with the KT.
So here whatever the parameters that are
required are placed here.
OK,
here in this task flow we are adding
source welfare query which will do almost
everything in the source welfare query
itself.
It will do transformation logics that are
performing that like that are happening
to source tables,
to source columns and look UPS on parent
tables to populate foreign key,
foreign key values and then look up on
target table for both forward dated
scenarios and back dated scenarios and
also change flag logic.
Everything is happening in the source 12
fair query only.
You'll get these details when you like.
Refer to the KT video where we have a
code walk through OK source call fair
query walk through OK after that using
that change flag here.
This expression is solely for error error
OK error handling.
So in this expression first is error
description.
OK here,
here I have for Let me show you all your
questions.
Job role assignment, we have 4 OK, OK,
we have 4, but here we have again OK,
four only.
So Ria the we in the job role assignment
for this particular broker party address
table we have four job rules assigned to
4 columns.
OK all are null cheques.
So what here we are doing this is a like
a thing which can be used like anywhere
but like this same code like this like
decode we have if here.
So we'll just check whether any of these
columns are coming as not all these are
source values.
If you have any foreign tree,
we will be checking the value of the
column which is used at the join
condition.
So for example,
if you take for broker party address,
broker party is the parent table.
While we are doing a lookup on this table,
Sam column from source would be would be
compared against business key column of
the broker party right?
Whatever the column that is used at that
part,
we have to use that column to validate
the null check for foreign key.
Here if you see broker party ID is there,
this is a foreign key.
In order to validate the null check for
this broker party ID,
we would be using the source party ID
which is the source column OK and for
address identifier reason code,
whatever the values that are being passed
from the source,
we are just validating if any of the
value is coming as Now what about the
broker party ID itself?
Can you go back to this DB?
Broker party ID is the primary key right?
Not foreign.
It's a foreign key in another.
This table is.
It's a foreign primary key in another
table, but it is foreign key.
OK,
what's taking in the parent table if it
is present, present on so further,
this is the target column name,
this is the source name,
and this is the value.
Here they're populating this as empty,
empty string.
But in the updated logic,
this is broker one.
But in CCO we are populating null,
hard coded null value because it is null,
right.
Instead of like empty space.
It's more meaningful if we pass a test
null, OK, OK, yeah,
we're just passing it as null.
If if we see this as null,
then we are hard coding it as null.
That's it.
That's the extra showing, nothing else.
And then coming back to here and then we
are just adding what will this one see?
OK, rule ID, rule ID from rule master job,
rule master from hard coded basically,
yeah, this is hard coded.
This is hard code in the sense based upon
the rule,
we have to assign it as it is in the like
in this stage mapping table level stage
mapping based upon the rule,
we have to add it accordingly.
It's a hard coded only.
We have to add it accordingly.
OK as it is a null check,
one is related to null check.
We have kept it as null.
And this represents the error severity
code.
OK critical.
If it is critical,
give C if it is informational,
you give I OK,
we have to do similarly for each and
every everything.
OK once this is done,
this is related to the error description.
OK and then error.
This is critical error check if any one
of this column is null only.
I have considered the critical columns.
Critical three are critical,
one is informational.
Right here I have considered only
critical columns.
If any one of this null I'm marking it as
Y else N OK and then this is just hard
coded values source database name,
source schema name,
source table name and then this is source
identifier like this is we have to
populate GRS unique ID here which is a
zone 1 table column like this just it's
just like a audit column in that table.
So it's it's holding some UUID value like
that.
So we have to populate this way as source
identifier, OK.
And so for all tables,
this is the same name.
Yeah, it might differ.
It might differ based upon the alias.
Here he has added SRC, right?
So it it might differ based upon the
alias.
But GRS,
I mean the actual name GRS unique ID,
correct?
Correct.
GRS unique ID is the actual column in
June 1.
And then if if the critical check is N
then it is a valid record,
otherwise it's a invalid record.
OK based upon this critical check,
if any one of this thing is null then we
are marking.
That's why if if there is any record with
any of these values with any of this
columns as null,
then it is a invalid record.
OK, this is the validation flag.
Are we good here Shreya?
OK, then here comes router.
In router the below 1 is directly we're
like using this flow for job run stats.
OK,
so we have to calculate source record
count and target and change record count
right?
As we have to update these details in the
job run stat.
So here we are doing that.
We're just grouping by using this job run
ID.
This will take all the records because
all the records will have the same job
run ID.
And here we are doing a count of one for
source record count and we're just
marking wherever we have change flag as
no change.
We are just marking it as one and doing
the sum aggregated sum here so that
overall it will give you the target
unchanged record count.
How change flag you are define change
flag is defined in the source welfare
query itself.
I told you right,
most of the logic is in the source
welfare query that joins change flag
logic, handling bag data scenarios.
Everything will be in end to end.
It is like disgusting.
One of our videos.
Yeah, yeah.
It should be like end to end in the sense,
not completely end to end.
These are parts handled by different
people, right?
As part of ABC,
ABC and ABC integration with the build.
Those are discussed separately and
metadata entries,
whatever parameter file related to build
in the high level.
But source welfare query is itself a very
complex and it's very exhaustive.
So it is explained differently and it is
developed by Bharat.
So he he has given,
he has provided the KT.
OK, OK.
So he can, so he can, yeah.
It's it should be in the recordings
folder only,
but it is not accessible currently, right?
Let's see after some time or check,
let's check with some.
OK,
so this is how we have to calculate the
source code count and target and change
record count.
Once we get these two values we are
populating.
So here we are whatever the ABC table
that you see here are from Snowflake.
As we have to implement full push down
optimization for source to stage load,
we are having temporary tables from
Snowflake itself.
We are we are not using our tables
directly to update them.
OK here we have job run, start step,
timetable which will have columns like
this job ID, execution run ID, job run.
How we are, I mean how is the flow,
how we are like doing what when,
what value usually we are populating and
what are the updates that we are doing.
So initially the entry we are making in
the Adoda table, right,
initial manual entries and anything.
Now here in the stage mapping we are
making entries into Snowflake table in
post load job post load.
We would be using these entries from job
Snowflake and we'll update the entries
which are made in the preload which are
made in the preload OK will be updated in
the post load using this I think preload
the job entries and all where loaded in
both snowflake and Aurora table right?
No.
OK, let me tell you clearly.
In the preload we are making entries into
3 tables Job run stats.
We are making it into Aurora directly.
OK, I'm leaving job error stats apart.
It's error log table, I'm not touching it.
And you understand its purpose, right?
Aria job error stats.
Yeah, leaving that apart,
main 3 tables job run stats.
In the job run stats preload we would be
loading it into job run stats only.
In ETL data injection source window we
would be loading to both Aurora and
Snowflake tables.
OK as we could be using the table to get
the sourcing start time and sourcing end
time.
In the source to stage load we we are
loading it into both tables.
OK, forgot it.
And then and then one equal execution.
So when you're let's come to the source.
OK, Yeah,
let's complete only one thing job rule
execution log.
We will be making entry only into our
order table and we will be updating in
our order table only.
We don't have any temporary table for
this table in Snowflake.
Yeah, I'm good.
You,
you can ask your question for job
execution now.
So there is no temporary table and error
like that's or something was also there
that that is also not needed for it is
there job rule error detail temp is there
and job rule error detail is there.
These two are separate tables.
These two are no separate tables means
I'm saying it's no,
it's no flick table Snowflake.
Yeah, yeah,
Snowflake table we have for job rule
error detail for job rule execution log.
We don't have timetable.
These two tables are different.
Now my question is when in the sourcing
window,
mission window even loading the data into
the snowflake right for job run status.
So like how are you doing it for for the
Arora table,
the entry was already there from preload.
So you will be updating it right?
Whatever with whatever the window and in
the in the job post whatever it say no
job preload the source window section you
say no that the source window will be
updated that we we like we discussed in
the last meeting.
So my question is,
suppose it is loading both problem status,
right?
One is Adora 1 is Nokia.
So Adora is fine because the entry will
already be existing,
it will just update the sourcing window,
right?
And what about this snowflake I'm not
getting?
I'm not getting your question,
but I'm repeating it again.
Real tail end to end high level where the
entries are making where into snowflake
where what is updating and post load?
OK again, OK,
just just pay some attention.
OK,
so in the job preload entries as part of
job run stats preload entry is made into
Aurora job run stats table.
OK,
in the second step for ETL data injection
source window,
entries will be made into both Aurora ETL
data injection source window and
Snowflake ETL data injection source
window.
Third step here entries will be made into
Aurora, the job rule execution log table.
OK, this here we completed job load,
job preload.
Now in the job load all the entries would
be made into snowflake temp tables.
I'll tell you the names now.
OK job run stats temp it will just hold
source record count and target unchanged
record count along with audit columns and
job ID, job run ID,
execution run ID OK Next table is balance
reconciliation stats stem table.
This will hold source related source
related concatenated string which will
have source related amount column names
and corresponding values OK,
corresponding aggregated sum values.
These along with audit columns and job ID,
job run ID,
execution run ID OK and job rule error
detail temp which will hold details error
details at record level.
This you know OK and that's it.
This these three are the these 3 or 4
three only I told you are these three are
the temporary snowflake tables.
So ABC related in this like in this state
main task flow this first state OK,
so even loading the job run status into
the snowflake timetable, right.
So here what about the job start time and
all which was loaded from payload.
We are not loading it here.
I told you that we're just loading the
Yeah, OK.
That's what I'm I'm trying to understand
that we are taking it's from the existing
ABC table or we are just loading the
necessary details only.
Yeah, OK, here we are loading job ID,
execution run ID, job run ID,
source record con,
target record con along with audit
columns.
OK.
So whatever was like loaded as part of
preload.
So that data will be updated again in the
in the next or following slip, right.
OK.
When it's loaded in the slope post load,
yes,
it will be updated in the post code based
upon the target table.
Yeah,
records and this timetables OK in general,
thank you to ask this only OK, OK, OK,
then do it.
So here,
this is stage table where they are
loading all the details here.
I just want to mention one thing here.
We have audit columns like audit batch ID,
audit job ID OK.
These two columns we have to populate
execution run ID and job run ID OK
because these two columns might confuse
you.
That is the reason why I'm just saying we
have to add run,
run IDs here OK while making any insert,
insert like while performing any insert
operation entry should be made into like
a value should be populated to row create
date time row update date time row
created by user ID,
row operation by user ID for insert
operation OK This you already know like
it is similar to audit create date time,
audit update date time OK or created by
user or it is a type 2 table.
It's a type 2 table.
All these values should be loaded during
update operation.
Only created by updated by should be
updated along with batch ID and job ID.
OK Batch ID and job ID should also be
updates for during update operation.
OK I'm just telling you why it is
execution run ID in the batch ID that you
mentioned.
That is as per the design.
Oh here we have to populate run IDs only
now that is the reason why we are
populating execution run ID as here in LM
we are using this execution run ID to
have it in each and every table right?
We are not much using batch run ID anyway
it's just a primary key.
But we are using execution run ID to
handle restart process also right?
So this is the design Nidhika told to
populate this value into audit batch ID
and job ID has job ID OK here in stage
always it would be a truncate and load
table.
It's a truncate and load stage is a
truncate and load.
OK.
And then coming to temporary here RA,
RA in the sense differential integrity.
So here I'll give you a high level view
details of this available differential
integrity In the sense if you are doing a
lookup on any parent table and you don't
find that record like corresponding
business key in the parent table,
then whatever the source record that we
are using it,
it falls under RA and it will be loaded
into this table.
OK, I'll, I'll show you that party ID.
If it is not present then it will fall
into this array table, correct, Correct.
So if you see is null of party IDFK.
So they are populating FK value to this
column.
So yeah,
they are checking if it is if it is null
or not.
And also they are checking if it if the
record is valid.
If the record is valid then only they'll
populate into here.
And in the first one stage records.
Here we are populating the records
without our issue.
The records which are which are which are
valid like we are not populating the
records which are invalid and we are not
populating the no change records, OK.
What is that?
Sorry oh, what is null source Patty ID OK.
And so here we are excluding the records
which are having the RA issue.
Not is null in the sense we are just
taking the records for which FK is
populated with some true value.
OK.
But one question,
so this RI records right is now SRC party
IDFC and O valuations like first to valid.
But if that's according key means the
value or party ID from this correct on
the current key value, OK,
primary key value of the parent table.
And here in the error check,
we are considering the business key value
coming from the source.
And here it is the actual table value,
correct?
Actual PK FK value that are that we are
populating.
OK, you are good with these two, right?
Yeah.
And let me show you the structure of like
how we are mapping this step here
sequence they are not they have not
mapped.
Not sure why this column is also I don't
know job ID should be populated with job
ID and this is target down to table name.
This is child should be populated with
audit John one UUID.
This you have to check like for this you
have to go through the the logic 1/3 and
then only you'll understand how this
value is being populated.
This is 1 basically and then it is coming
from the source Qualfare query.
Yeah, we are just concatenating some GRS.
That's fine.
I will check the query.
Just logically I'm asking what is the
thing logically it's it,
it is just a UUID column,
GRS unique ID is there, right.
So they are prefixing them,
prefixing it with some, you know, like it.
They're converting that.
They are populating some variant value,
variant in the sense some Jason kind of
thing.
Value would be GRS unique ID,
but the key would be UUID,
something they are populating for this
call.
OK, it's a variant column.
It will hold a Jason context.
I can show you how it looks.
I'll show you.
Yeah, sorry.
Oh, for this table you might not see.
For one table, I see.
For client, I guess client, I think I see.
I'll be back in a minute.
OK, OK.
Well, project file uploading live.
If that I should.
So if you see here I have just queried
temporary table OK this is how child
looks like.
This is UAID value and this we will frame
using source table name.
And so this is kind of a like key column
kind of yeah,
this is kind of a primary key column in
zone 1 table parent is the primary key
column of the parent.
No, no, no, no, not parent source.
OK, parent you are saying oh,
parent I also I'll show you it.
It will have all the parent table name
and parent a business key,
column name and column value.
So this is the value that we are getting
from the source.
So so like it is sorted to RA just
because we don't find this value in this
agreement table for this column correct.
So this is just informational thing that
we are asked to offer parent related
information will be there here.
Hello.
Yeah, yeah,
I can hear that you got it right.
No, you're check you're seeing it.
OK, OK,
so these are taken from the zone 1 table,
not zone 1 table.
These will be populated from the source
welfare query.
So yeah, but there it is.
Same.
We frame.
Yeah, yeah.
Like this is hard coded.
This is hard coded or might be
parameterized which might be taking from
the parameter file or we can do hard
coded also and this value is from the
source zone one also.
But we the value format being created in
the source file for query, correct?
Correct.
Yes.
Oh,
I thought it is as it is from the source
zone.
No, we didn't want to.
Agreement is the table name.
So what's the agreement?
Agreement is the payment table name.
Agreement is the parent.
This is column business business key name
which is used at the join and this is the
value that which is being compared
against this column in the query.
OK and target key column names and target
key column values key column names.
Here we are populate inflict here they
are populating with source key columns
and corresponding source values.
I know the name says John 2,
but they're populating source only so
that if they if they try to these are
just informational columns.
I have already traced this with Ned
because they told it's fine as they are
just informational columns like that.
The what is what?
What will this hold Like will it hold the
party ID name and party ID fellow?
Oh, they're popular.
OK, I think.
Let me take one of my.
OK,
if you see here Chail Jonto these are my
address ID,
address business effect relate are my
source business case and corresponding
source values.
OK, OK.
This values we we are these are test
informational columns which we would be
used to check these particular like this
particular values in these tables using
these like whether this record is present,
if it is present how the data like that
some like if you want to like analyse
further we can use these values.
These are just informational values we
are asked to populate like this.
OK, OK yeah.
And then yeah, that's it.
These are just audit columns.
Next going next moving to error group.
So here in the error we are taking both
in critical and critical and information
on the records.
So if my validation flag is invalid it it
means there is some issue with the record
Critical issue like critical leakage
check is failed for that record if like
as we are including informational related
information also in the error description
we are using not is null of error
description.
This implies if if it is null then there
is no issue.
If it is not is null,
there is some issue either with critical
or information, OK.
If any one of these is false,
there are records which might have only
informational issue,
informational check issue then also it
should load it.
It should be loaded into both error group
and stage stage record.
That is the reason why we are explicitly
calling these critical issues with the
flag.
Whereas informational we are using this
error description directly OK and balance
frequency OK.
Let me give you OK here in the field
mapping I'll job ID,
job execution run ID and job run ID that
source, database name, source schema name,
source table name,
source record identifier and error
description.
All these columns we have were created in
the expression transformations and these
are just from these audit columns.
And then last balance sheet installation,
we would be doing balancing calculations
only for the records that are intended to
be loaded into the target, correct?
That is the reason why we have same
whatever the group that we are using,
we're using the same group here.
We can also OK, this is exactly same.
We we have just used this and this OK we
have just used it in a reverse order.
Here we are using not equal to invalid
here we have used it this we can use the
same group to populate here also.
But earlier we have not implemented this
like whole logic like this.
We might there is some like there is some
other logic.
So we have just updated it, OK,
can use the same group, OK.
And here at this point like here as it is
loading the data,
there is no such calculation yet, right?
The source value like threshold value and
all those will come later, right?
At this point, everything will be loaded,
everything OK one minute.
So here we would be calculating the
aggregated values or the source records
and we would be framing one expression
and we are sending that expression as
part of the entry into balance
reconciliation stat stamp table.
OK.
Here actually we don't have balance
reconciliation for broker for,
but for testing purposes,
we have just mocked up 1 balance
reconciliation check that is count check.
So here count and amount cheques are
there, right?
I told you right.
If we want to do any distinct count check
of a particular column that is coming
from the source and also after load how
it how many records distant count it is
there.
So that check we are doing that,
but mostly we'll have amount columns only.
Yeah.
So as there are no amount columns in this
table,
we have performed this for the for the
exchange check like we have just user
some sorter to do distinct and we are
allowing only specific columns like this.
This is just so some ETL log.
OK so if there was two amount columns one
and one count check then there will be 3
entries and this can be countable correct?
And we have to like frame this ETL
pipelines also accordingly, OK, OK.
And the target calculation in this state
will be done or no, No,
in the in the balance reconciliation only
it will be done.
We would be using one expression from the
parameter file based upon that two
expressions,
there are two actually we are using two
parameters not parameters from the
parameter file for that calculation.
I'll tell you OK,
I'll tell you there so far.
No,
we have just we are just doing the count
here using the segregation transformation.
We are just doing performing the count,
OK.
If the count is null,
then we are just taking it as a zero.
In case if, if there is no record,
then it would be null, right.
And then here in the expression,
in the expression,
we are just creating the expression as we
have only one.
We have just created this if if we have
multiple then we have to concatenate like
this some call.
So before that we should have pipe symbol
and call to like this and then we have to
concatenate with the call call to value
like this.
OK this is the expression like based upon
the number of columns.
So it would be added.
OK,
I have provided this information in this
LLD I guess.
And the job load,
I have provided this information.
OK, I'll sorry,
I think I forgot to give you the glimpse
of LLD first and going to the Idms you
could directly jump to IDMC.
OK,
I'll just cover this balance
reconciliation and I'll come to.
Hello, Ria.
Yeah, I'm not staying between.
Oh, is it I, I,
I'm literally apologising you for not
covering LLD first and getting into IDMC
directly.
Hello.
Yeah, yeah, Yes, Sir.
Like if we have multiple balance
reconciliation metrics,
we just need to concatenate these like
this.
I'm telling.
And also I'm informing you that I have
added this point in the LLD here.
OK, I'll, I'll,
I'll give you a walkthrough in the L&
D later, OK?
This is how we have to prepare the
expression.
That's why one more thing here.
What are the values?
Can you show me one sample entry Cancel
and see that you have in the table count
layer target database name,
target schema name, target table name,
target column name these 4 columns we are
not choosing and threshold type,
threshold value and active indicator and
audit fails.
And hello is where are this?
I mean actual value, actual found values.
Where are this in the description?
I didn't get to moving Nokia for that day.
We were showing 1 description, right?
The column name value or something.
You go, you go to.
OK, yeah, that is in LLD.
No, no, not in LD.
So go to,
go to the mapping one and show me that.
Show me the transformation.
Very, very concatenating value.
This broke a party ID you're asking?
Yeah.
So here only source level count or source
level amounts we are adding and target
level, it will be done later.
Is it correct,
correct here as we are as we as we,
we are doing the balancing metric for
this target column.
We have added this broker party ID here.
But the actual value I'm talking about
suppose the this is the,
this is the one which is sound for source,
right?
Not target.
Yeah, one minute.
Yeah, I got you.
So here we have to provide that target
table name only.
But here count should be from the source
records,
whatever the records that are coming out
of the source qualified query and which
are not having no change flag and which
are not invalid like which are just valid
records.
We are considering those records and we
are doing the aggregated count,
extinct count of it correct of the source
records only.
But here we have to populate the target,
the column value only, column name,
name OK.
And once that expression is created,
we're just populating the gate level,
target level count and all will be done
via job poster or valid column.
It will be no,
no target insert record con,
update record con.
If you're speaking about that,
it will be done in the job runsters
postal.
You're talking about that only, right?
No, no Bell record.
Suppose for Bell record,
this sound check you are doing right?
You entered the source record count from
this mapping and from where the target
record count will be like load updated
from the Bell record table from No, no,
no, no, no.
OK, one minute.
Yeah.
So I'm just getting confused.
You are talking about balance
reconciliation only.
Let me tell you.
So source record count we're we're
calculating it and making entry into
balance reconciliation temp table in
smoothly.
OK.
We'll use this table and using the
expressions that we have in the parameter
file and target table directly to
calculate the balancing metrics in the
balance reconciliation only.
And also we will be using this timetable
to compare the source record values,
target values.
And at once we would be making insert
into balance reconciliation stats table.
OK, source, target value, source value,
out of balance value, flag values,
balancing flag and within threshold flag,
all these values we would be doing only
at once in the balance reconciliation
step, cancellation step, a step.
It's it's part of post load.
It's part of post load.
Yeah, Yeah, that's what I'm trying to ask.
Yeah.
Post load or OK, OK,
I'm just getting confused.
Oh, sorry.
So this is source aggregated text,
we are just populating into balance
reconciliation temp table.
OK, got it.
Yeah,
we are done with the ABC integration that
needs to be done at the in the job level.
This temp are is also we are keeping I
told you right we are keeping it as part
of APC only.
But we'll have temp are a table main are
a table both in snowflake only.
We don't have them in Aurora as it is a
reusable code.
That's why I'm asking me to keep it as
part of job post.
OK, OK,
OK then let let me give you a box drop
them quickly in the Lily also whatever we
have discussed so far.
OK in the job load the process cheques if
the stage table is already loaded in case
of a restart.
So I told you right,
we would be calculating the record count
of stage table in the source and in like
sorry in the job reload.
And if there are any records in case of a
restart,
if there are records already present in
the stage table for the given for the
current job run ID,
then we would be skipping the stage table.
This we are just telling first this loads
data from source to stage along with the
calculation of counts, balance metrics,
performing data validation tricks, if any.
I'm processing RA records.
OK,
these steps like I these are the sub
steps.
I'm just explaining each in in 1 by 1.
So first it will the step starts by
taking like whatever the input parameters
that it is taking,
it is taking and it also reads the data
by selecting the records who's modified
date not modified date.
Here I'll take watermark column because
earlier they told it would be same across.
But now I can see they are take they're
considering some watermark columns.
OK, watermark column or oh date column.
Function OK this is this is keeps on
changing RIA.
It's just I'm trying to say first the
incrementing data, that's it.
After the source data it it,
it performs validation ticks.
I told you right in the expression
transformation, if any, we use error,
error severity code.
We use error severity code to indicate
it's a graph release to indicate whether
an error check is critical or information.
If that record fails critical validation
check that records is sent to job rule,
error detail timetable and it's not
loaded into target table.
If a record fails an informational
validation check,
that record is logged into both error
detail and also into the target table.
Here target table in the sense stays
stiff OK.
But functionally high level it would be
in the target tablet.
That's why we haven't.
If any critical validation rules are
later deactivated in the job rule
assignment table,
the validation logic should be reviewed
and update to make sure the processing
behaviour still matches the active rules.
This if we are making we have is active
flag rate if we are deactivating directly
in the job rule assignment.
But if we are not revising the logic and
the mapping,
it will still fails right as we are doing
everything in within the ATL logic.
That's what I mentioned here as a note.
OK, what is not typical validation?
If any critical validation is unrelated
the activity, the validation law,
we should be removed and updated to make
sure for some DMS to not use the activity.
I I didn't get it like, OK,
it is already pulling the active flag.
I'll tell you, I'll tell you,
you will get it, I'll tell you.
OK, so for example,
I have this critical cheques, right?
These three,
I have marked all these as active.
I don't want the broker party ID null
check.
I'll deactivate it here,
but I didn't do any change in this error
like in this market.
What happened?
It will if any value is coming as null
from the source, what it will do?
It won't do.
It will it will load into target, right?
It will, sorry, it won't load into target,
right.
But we don't want it to be loaded like
not to be loaded into the target.
We are accepting it and we are treating
it as a normal thing and we want it to be
loaded.
This is not working properly, right?
What we what do we need to do?
We have to revise the code here in the
logic we have to remove.
If we don't want this,
we have to remove this logic whatever
related to them.
That's what I meant to say with that with
those lines.
OK.
And then it then job level counts.
And so it then it then calculates job
level counts,
the job level source record count.
This includes source record count,
which shows how many reports right from
the source and target which shows how
many records were rejected during the
load.
And we are would be loading this into job
run starts.
And it also prefers balancing metrics for
for reconciliation, if any.
I'm just keeping if any if.
If there are any records then only we
have to do this balance reconciliation
flow.
It calculates the source side aggregated
values and stored them in a text format
such as column one column aggregated
value like this we are we are doing it
right.
This value is inserted into balance sheet
cancellation timetable.
Source balance metrics would be
calculated for the valid records except
error unchanged on our reports that it
route OK.
This is the third step, this three,
after that it routes RA records into
temporary RA table, OK,
this and then the next,
the next day data is loaded from the
source from stage to target.
Input values are populated OK for new
records, yeah, here the input values,
your run ID,
all these values are populated to for new
records.
For updated records,
both audit fields are both,
both audit fields are refreshed with the
current run values.
So whatever the audit fields that I have
given, right.
So for updated records,
we have to update the audit batch for the
job ID.
OK, that's one question.
This stage table,
this is source to stage table that you
are showing me, right?
This mapping is first source to stage.
We would be doing ABC integration in this
mapping only I'll show you the stage to
target one second before that.
OK,
So this is the stage table is trunk it
and load right and insert only every time
this stage is trunk it.
Yeah, it's it's trunk it and reload.
Oh.
I'll show you the target properties.
It is truncate and reload.
What this idea change and from stage 2
target and the actual type 1 and type 2
whatever is there?
Yeah, yeah, it would be implemented.
It's a truncate table,
truncate and reload.
OK, got it.
From stage 2 target.
They're using some merge query.
OK,
they're using some merge query and the
source qualifier itself to to perform the
upset operation.
OK, this is just nothing.
Just source philtre, target philtre here.
Just we are blocking the request.
Show me once the Yeah, I'll I'll show you.
Yeah, yeah.
This is this is the stage,
Stage 2 target mapping.
I'll show you the stage table one minute.
So this is stage 2 target mapping.
Here we have the merge query which will
perform insert update all the operations
using the sequel query only.
And here we have a philtre which will
just block.
And this is a dummy target.
That's it.
And here for the target stage 2 target
full PDO is not working.
So what we are doing is we are just
enabled full video and we are not asking
like we are not checking this create time
view because it is giving issue.
It's not a normal select statement, right?
It is merged, right?
Something is not working.
That is the reason why we disabled this.
OK, sure.
And then you have one question.
Yeah, stage stable.
I do you want to see stage stable?
Yeah, Query also.
Yeah, query also.
Just give me like at a glance.
Just show me one.
OK, OK, OK, OK.
I'm giving you account, party address.
These are OK CCO.
OK, sorry,
can you open the source verified query
once?
I will just take a look.
OK,
which one stage to target 1 both actually
just we'll take a look.
Hey, I think I have them handy here.
Let me stage to target now.
Oh, I got this.
So let's take it for another.
And about this deduplication and other,
is there any recording for that as well?
Yeah,
these two are developed by Bharat
initially.
So there should be recordings,
but you have to see which is the latest
recording.
So here we are doing a merge into target
table using.
This is again a CPE.
So first we are trying to get all the
values from the source.
And here we are doing one,
one thing for row effect,
for row effect to date time, what here,
here what we are doing is so from source
is also a type 2 table.
So in that case,
what we'll do if there is any change,
we'll have two entries,
we have two records.
So for example,
I got a record on 29th July, OK.
And I'll have that report in my target.
And there is a change today that first
you like there is a change for that
record and how the data will get will get
2 records again.
Because in in my source as it is a type 2
table,
its record gets updated and the other
record is inserted.
So when we fetch the incremental load
incremental data,
how many requests do we get?
We get 2 records.
Whatever the record which is in
deactivated state,
we mark it as update expiration rate.
And whatever the other record which is
newly inserted as part of source load,
we would be taking it as a insert.
OK.
So whatever the record with update
expiration rate,
we are just updating it with the source
like target active row effect to date and
row this like this you will get once you
go through the source to stage query this.
We are doing it here.
It's just like whenever we are updating,
whenever we are updating that record,
updating that record row expiration date,
OK, to affect to date, OK, So OK,
So whenever we are making the new entry,
right,
whatever the row affect to date that we
have in the source should be, it's OK, OK,
while while we are making the new insert,
the row affect to date should be the
previous expiration date, right?
Yeah,
I think something is happening here that
is happening here, OK, We,
we have to go through the codec India.
But what I want,
what I'm trying to say is whenever this
is there,
then they're just treating the effective
date like that.
I don't know, I'm getting anxious.
OK, you can check with,
but it's recording video or the basic,
you can actually check with him, OK.
And we are just taking all the columns
from the stage and then we here we are
generating one sequence generation only
for the records,
OK or like for insert reports,
we are we have to assign a a sequence
generated value, right?
And also here what we are doing for every
key,
there will be only one one sequence
number.
That's what Nidhika told in the morning.
So I so for example,
that is a business key key one which is
loaded and to target 5 and today again it
loaded.
So the two records will have the same
primary key.
OK, That's how that's what done it.
Look it told me so all that sequence is
same, right?
Even business key is same and again
they're keeping the key also same.
Not sure why.
OK.
So this is the one like here within this
logic they are doing that and after that
this is a merge join condition.
So they're just taking all the business
key columns of the target and draw out
the credit and source system.
OK, OK.
And then they're if if if the flag is
updated,
they're updating all the non key columns
and audit columns.
OK,
audit updated by the all these things and
all these are non key columns of the
target.
If it is just expiration update
expiration date,
they're just updating expiration date and
record indicator and audit update them.
And these four that's it.
If it is a zone one UUID,
they're just updating zone one UUID and
audit fails OK.
If it is insert OK.
If it is update expiration date and both,
then they are doing both.
They are doing both row expiration date.
They're updating both these to both OK
and the audit funds.
And if it is insert,
they are just making an insert and coming
to the source query.
This is how source query OK OK let me
take proper party address only as it is
the reference query that has to be
followed everywhere.
So you asked me to show this query.
So here first.
First they are deduplicating along with
the row of vector test.
So if there are any reports coming from
the source with the same, with the same,
with the same business key and row effect
to date,
they are completely duplicating it.
They are taking only one record in the
first step.
And also they're can you, can you,
can you come with that?
Sorry.
OK, So here they're in the first city.
They're trying to remove duplicate
records.
They are considering if there are any
reports with same business key and row
effect today,
then they are considering only one record.
They are taking only version record based
upon this row number function.
OK,
they are taking only the record with
highest ARH timestamp.
Most recent record only they are taking
in the first step along with their
passing some hard like parameters,
hardware values,
whatever and they're doing some
transformations that that needs to be
done here,
whatever the according to the mapping
logic.
And they're doing join with the ET, ET,
ET and detention source window table and
order to get the sourcing start time and
sourcing end time.
And they're adding that incremental
philtre here.
And they're doing a reprocessing of RA
reports whatever the records that are
routed to RA yesterday or previously
would be reprocessed again.
They are just they will just check
whether the incoming record like they
they are just adding,
they're just adding the records also from
the source.
OK, from the source they are.
They're also adding all the records which
are routed to RA previously.
OK, that's it.
They're ignoring deleted records and also
ignoring dead records whose raw effect to
date equal to expression date.
They they're ignoring OK in the second in
the second city they're calculating.
They're doing two things.
First one is they're doing a lookup on
the parent table to fetch the what is
this 2 fetch of foreign key value OK
foreign key value.
And the second one is they are
calculating hash,
current hash and previous hash OK and
they are doing a match and they are
deduplicating it if if there is any
report.
So here here while calculating the hash
and previous hash sure they are
considering only the business keys not
the row expiration date.
OK.
If there are any records with the same
business key but different traffic to
date, we are to.
We are checking the hash match,
the current hash in previous hash is
matching.
We are ignoring from it and we are giving
the version number to it.
OK it's like anaemic how we have done
that.
So there are only row effective bit and
row expiration date, right?
Is there any other that we are not sure?
Yeah,
that we are not sure as the row effect to
DT column is already present in the sort
they are considering this.
Whereas in CCO we are not considering
this.
We are considering some update value.
It depends on the functionality of the
system.
OK, hello.
Yeah, yeah, we are good right.
And then we are just calculating row
expiration date.
So if like for every our record,
our row expiration date would be like
next records row effect to date, right.
Usually if there is no next record then
we are giving high end date for the class
record OK and then John one UUID.
So here we are to using we are creating a
variant function Jason text with the
first would be source table name and John
one UUID.
And then this GRS.
This is used for RA while populating to
child column.
We are using this right.
And then RA parent.
So here per parent they we are using
parent table and source here it should be
source table name and like source column,
source key column names and source key
column values.
This is not like right?
Not like table.
Yeah, yeah, sorry here.
OK,
sorry for parent this is parent table and
parent business key and parent business
key value which which is ideally from the
pair source, right.
This is related to parents or I thought
it was key columns.
OK,
this this target to own two key columns
will have all this source key column
names.
And I think in the next CTS,
they will form the value.
They form the value.
OK,
These two are audit fields and what there
are few columns for which they're
populating enough.
This is as part of the mapping document
only.
You'll get it.
We're just bringing hash logics,
FQ columns, all these things,
OK and all these are just source columns.
After that we are bringing few columns
from the target, OK.
We are bringing all the requests from the
target, OK.
Here we are not not just bringing the
active report, OK.
And while doing target look up,
we are we would be doing in a in two ways.
First we are doing we are doing target
look up with along with business keys and
to date this is for back data scenario.
Then then we are doing this for active.
This is just normal.
I see you type how we would do.
We are doing it for just for the active
records this year and this is for the
back dated scenario.
And we have we have the calculation for
change flag.
We have the calculation for change flag
for forward dated records in final one.
In final two we have the calculator for
change flag in a back backdated records
and finally we are doing a union of those
two and we are bringing that as out of
the source welfare for change plan logic
area.
You have to go through this logics and
you have to understand it.
OK, Hello Hariha.
Oh,
where is doing the reverse engineering
and everything we are seeing building it
or like that, that thing is different,
that is different, that is different.
Reverse engineering part is different.
Earlier Kushi and Kavya was doing that
reverse engineering and all along with
Kai 3.
Now Kushi,
Kavya were also going to build and also
Kai 3 was taking care of the build.
I don't know who was working on reverse
engineering currently.
OK, so we are done so in the job level,
that's why I'm just showing we are done
with job preload and job load.
This this covers our stage load and
target table.
Only one thing pending is job post load
success and batch post load here in the
batch post here batch post load is
nothing.
I'll just try explain this quickly.
It it will just take the value and it
will update.
Yeah.
Otherwise, OK,
you you can you can keep it for later.
OK.
Later.
Yeah, yeah, OK then.
Yeah, because this is a lot.
So I had to I think job job like having
the most of the information.
Yeah,
job preload and job post load is sort of
high.
OK, I think we are good.
Yeah, like I'm done from my end.
Do you have any questions on this?
So job load not now.
But what I mean is like this different
type of mappings.
If you have any sample task right
supposed for type 2 and then for type 1.
So I I would need some different task so
that I can see the like different.
OK.
As of now we have only type 2 tables.
Yeah, OK.
And for type 2 tables in every cases the
source,
the source table is also type 2 table or
it can like it depends,
it depends on the function.
Then provide me those two like task flows
that source is type 2 and source type 2.
Like as of now we have only type 2 source
tables only per CCO.
I have worked on CCU and I just know few
details with Rocco.
That's it.
Whatever the task flow that I have given
right That is the same thing we are used
to given in CCU.
Both are having type 2,
type 2 source tables.
OK, you are you ping the task?
Yeah,
I ping the task flow name under the
domain like folder name in.
Have a good, yeah, I think.